A Finding Aid to the Adolph A. Weinman Papers, 1890-1959, in the Archives of American Art AAA.weinadol
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1896-circa 1955; Series 8; (Boxes 3-8, 10-14, OVs 15-22; Reels 5888-5891; 6.0 linear feet)
  - Glass Plate Negatives of Various Projects, 1896-1954, undated (Box 13)
    - Spandrel Figures Over Arch, undated (Box 10)
      2 glass plate negatives
    - Boys Holding Symbols of Industry, undated (Box 10)
    - Eagle on Sphere, undated (Box 10)
    - Grave Memorial for William Kimball, undated (Box 10)
      3 glass plate negatives
    - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences Pediment, undated (Box 10)
    - Through the Smoke of Battle, undated (Box 10)
    - Standing Lincoln with Hand on Lapel, undated (Box 10)
    - Weinman's Mother, Catharina Weinman, 1896 (Box 10)
      9 glass plate negatives
    - Sculptor's Mother, Portrait Medallion of Catharina Weinman, 1896 (Box 10)
    - Sculptor's Mother, Portrait Medallion of Catharina Weinman, 1896 (Box 13)
    - Portrait Medallion of Unidentified Man, circa 1900 (Box 10)
    - Bust of Margaret Lucille (sculptor's wife), circa 1900 (Box 10)
      6 glass plate negatives
    - Sarah Porter Memorial Plaque, 1901 (Box 10)
    - The Bowler, circa 1901 (Box 10)
      4 glass plate negatives
    - Girl Golfer, circa 1901 (Box 10)
    - The Golfer, 1901 (Box 10)
    - The Pitcher, 1901 (Box 10)
    - Rockinghorse Baby, 1902 (Box 11)
    - Bust of Charles Henry Niehaus, 1903 (Box 11)
    - Strayed From the Herd, circa 1903 (Box 11)
    - Cow with Lowered Head, circa 1903 (Box 11)
    - Chief Flatiron, 1903-1904 (Box 11)
    - Destiny of the Red Man, 1903-1904 (Box 11)
    - Kansas, circa 1904 (Box 11)
      5 glass plate negatives
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition Gold Medal, 1904-1905 (Box 11)
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition Silver Medal, 1904-1905 (Box 11)
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Plaque for Universal Exposition, 1904-1905 (Box 11)
    - Louisiana Purchase Exposition Bronze Medal, 1904-1905 (Box 11)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural Medal, 1905 (Box 11)
    - Panels for Façade of J. Pierpont Morgan Library, 1905 (Box 11)
    - George Poell Medal for Lifesaving on Railroads, 1905-1906 (Box 11)
    - Madison Square Presbyterian Church Pediment, circa 1906 (Box 11)
    - Alexander Macomb Memorial, 1906-1908 (Box 11)
    - Union Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Baltimore, Maryland, 1907-1912 (Box 11)
    - Union Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Baltimore, Maryland, 1907-1912 (Box 13)
    - Seated Lincoln Statue, Hodgenville, Kentucky, 1907-circa 1955 (Box 13)
    - Seated Lincoln Statue, Hodgenville, Kentucky, 1907-circa 1955 (Box 11)
    - William Bateman Leeds Mausoleum Panel, 1908 (Box 11)
    - Alexander Johnston Cassatt Statue, 1908-1910 (Box 12)
    - Seated Lincoln Statue, Madison, Wisconsin, 1908-1913 (Box 12)
    - Wisconsin State Capitol Pediment, 1909 (Box 12)
    - Eagle, Pennsylvania Railroad Station, New York, New York, 1910 (Box 12)
    - Swag with Winged Wheel, Pennsylvania Railroad Station, New York, New York, 1910 (Box 12)
    - Female Figure Holding Cornucopia and Winged Wheel, Pennsylvania Railroad Station, New York, New York, 1910 (Box 12)
    - Mercury Holding Cadeusus Keystone, Pennsylvania Railroad Station, New York, New York, 1910 (Box 12)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters Medal, circa 1910 (Box 12)
    - Relief Portrait of Gilbert Montague Stark, circa 1910 (Box 12)
    - Julius Theodore Melchers Memorial Plaque, 1910 (Box 12)
    - Standing Lincoln Statue, Frankfort, Kentucky, 1910-1917 (Box 12)
    - William Cotter Maybury Memorial, 1911-1912 (Box 12)
    - Municipal Building Sculpture, New York, New York, 1911-1913 (Box 12)
    - Masonic Temple Tympanum, San Francisco, California, 1912 (Box 12)
    - Lincoln Bust (Replica for Loraine Pratt-Immen), Grand Rapids, Michigan, 1912 (Box 12)
    - William F. Vilas Memorial, Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1912-1914 (Box 12)
    - Ancient Egyptian Sphinxes for Scottish Rite Temple, Washington, D. C., 1912-1915 (Box 12)
    - Sphinxes and Crowned Eagle, Scottish Rite Temple, Washington, D. C., 1912-1915 (Box 12)
      10 glass plate negatives
    - Sphinxes and Crowned Eagle, Scottish Rite Temple, Washington, D. C., 1912-1915 (Box 13)
    - Sir Galahad Sculptured Lectern, Pomfret, Connecticut, circa 1913 (Box 13)
    - Reredos with Kneeling Angels, George Newhall Clarke Memorial Chapel, Pomfret, Connecticut, 1913 (Box 13)
    - The Rising Sun and Descending Night, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1913-1916 (Box 13)
      11 glass plate negatives
    - Winged Liberty ("Mercury") Dime, 1916-1917 (Box 13)
    - J. Sanford Saltus Medal, circa 1921 (Box 13)
    - Missouri State Capitol Pediment, 1921-1926 (Box 13)
    - Elks National Memorial Headquarters Building Frieze and Façade Figures, Chicago, Illinois, 1923-1954 (Box 13)
    - Relocation of Sculpture by Karl Bitter and Fountain, Missouri State Capitol, Jefferson City, Missouri, 1925-1928 (Box 13)
    - Samuel Rea Statue, Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal, New York, New York, 1926-1930 (Box 13)
      8 glass plate negatives
  - Oversize Duplicate Photographs of Aphrodite, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawings for Union Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Baltimore, Maryland, 1907-1912; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawings of Seated Lincoln Statue, Hodgenville, Kentucky, 1907-circa 1955; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawings of Monument to Civil War Soldiers and Sailors, Albany, New York, 1909; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawing for Unidentified Tablet, 1910; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Duplicate Photographs of William F. Vilas Memorial, Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1912-1914; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Letter Concerning Memorial Tablet, Soldiers Welcome Home Committee, Forest Hills, New York, 1919-1921; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Photograph of Benjamin Harrison for Bust of Benjamin Harrison, John Herron Art Institute, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1920-1921; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Duplicate Photographs of Singer of the Epic Song, circa 1924; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5889)
  - Oversize Photographs of Samuel Rea Statue for Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal, New York, New York, 1926-1930; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5889)
  - Oversize Duplicate Photograph of William C. C. Claiborne Statue, State Capitol Building, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1930-1933; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5890)
  - Oversize Drawing of Mary A. Spencer Grave Memorial, Washington, D. C., 1936-1941; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5891)
  - Oversize Blueprint of Seated Lincoln Statue, Madison, Wisconsin, 1908-1913; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawings for Scottish Rite Temple, Washington, D. C., 1912-1915; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawing of Descending Night, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1913-1916; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Blueprint for Bust of Horace Mann, New York University Hall of Fame, 1922-1934; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Blueprint of Fountain for Missouri State Capitol, Jefferson City, Missouri, 1925-1928; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5889)
  - Oversize Blueprint for Monfaucon American Memorial, France, 1928-1932; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5889)
  - Oversize Blueprint for William C. C. Claiborne Statue, State Capitol Building, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1930-1933; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890)
  - Oversize Blueprints for The Last Farewell Figure, Arlington National Cemetery, Arlington, Virginia, 1929-1953; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890)
  - Oversize Drawing and Blueprints for U. S. Post Office Department Pediments, Washington, D. C., 1931-1935; (see also OV 20) (Reel 5890)
  - Oversize Blueprints for Oscar S. Straus Memorial, Washington, D. C., 1931-1948; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891)
  - Oversize Drawings for Jefferson Memorial Competition and Pediment, Washington, D. C., 1937-1943; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891)
  - Oversize Drawings, Blueprint, and Duplicate Photographs for Riders of the Dawn, Brookgreen Gardens, Brookgreen, South Carolina, 1941-1946; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5891)
  - Oversize Drawings and Blueprint for Seated Lincoln, Hodgenville, Kentucky, 1907-circa 1955; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawing for William Cotter Maybury Memorial, 1911-1912; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Drawings and Blueprints for The Last Farewell Figure, Arlington National Cemetery, Arlington, Virginia, 1929-1953; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5890)
  - Oversize Photograph for National Archives Pediment, Washington, D. C., 1933-1935; (see also OV 22) (Reel 5891)
- Printed Material, 1891-1959; Series 9; (Box 8, OV 21; Reel 5892; 0.4 linear feet)
  Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition catalogs for others, a program, a book, and miscellaneous art-related booklets.
  - Clippings, 1905-1922, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 318-411)
  - Clippings, 1923-1959 (Reel 5892, Frame 412-471)
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Others, 1945-1948 (Reel 5892, Frame 472-483)
  - Program for Presentation of Clinedinst Medal to Kurt H. Volk, 1950 (Reel 5892, Frame 484-486)
  - Book Anatomie Artistique du Corps Humain, 1891 (Reel 5892, Frame 487-490)
  - Booklets (Reel 5892)
    - "The Later Works of Augustus Saint-Gaudens" by Homer Saint Gaudens, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 492-505)
    - "Chesterwood: The Studio of Daniel Chester French,", undated (Reel 5892, Frame 506-508)
    - "The Equestrian Statues of the World,", 1913 (Reel 5892, Frame 509-526)
    - "The Medallic Work of A. A. Weinman,", 1921 (Reel 5892, Frame 527-556)
    - "The Washington of the Future,", 1930 (Reel 5892, Frame 557-568)
    - Miscellaneous Booklets from Brookgreen Gardens, 1937-1943 (Reel 5892, Frame 569-577)
    - "National Institute of Arts and Letters,", 1941 (Reel 5892, Frame 578-598)
    - Miscellaneous Booklets, 1901-1931 (Reel 5892, Frame 599-613)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 614-617)
  - Oversize Printed Reproduction of an Anatomical Drawing, (see also OV 21) (Reel 5892)
- Photographs, 1903-1950; Series 10; (Boxes 9, 13, OV 21; Reel 5892; 0.2 linear feet)
  Photographs of Weinman, his colleagues, his residence, and miscellaneous locations not directly related to specific projects. Photographs of Weinman with colleagues include Charles Keck and Charles Niehaus as well as views of Philip Martiny's studio, Charles Niehaus's studio, and the Roman Bronze Works. Photographs of Weinman's Forest Hills Residence/Studio include photos of a map to that location. Glass plates are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photographs of Adolph Weinman, 1903-1950; (4 folders; see also Box 13) (Reel 5892, Frame 620-655)
  - Photographs of Weinman with Colleagues, undated; (4 folders) (Reel 5892, Frame 656-675)
  - Photographs of Weinman's Forest Hills Residence/Studio, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 676-682)
  - Photographs of Brookgreen Gardens, Brookgreen, South Carolina, undated (Reel 5892, Frame 683-692)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5892, Frame 693-696)
  - Adolph Weinman, circa 1915 (Box 13)
  - Oversize Photograph of an Unidentified Monument, undated; (see also OV 21) (Reel 5892, Frame 697)